Contact

nedim.celebic@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nedim-celebic-phd-emba-28a83453 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Strategic Planning
Management Consulting
Project Management

Languages

English

Publications

Delegiranje autoriteta za odlučivanje sa top menadžmenta na srednji menadžment: slučaj srednjih preduzeća u Federaciji Bosne i Hercegovine

Percepcija o ulozi srednjeg menadžmenta u procesu strateškog odlučivanja

Nedim Celebic PhD, EMBA

Entrepreneur | Vice Rector | Startup Mentor | Development Management Expert

Bosnia and Herzegovina

Summary

Experienced in: economic, social and environmental development;

Specific experience in the following fields: SME, public administration, education, environment, police, military, agriculture, judiciary, energy, mining, labor, social policies, IT, health services;

Experienced in: marketing and market research, strategic and action planning: counseling, training, seminars; human resource management: assessment of needs for training, plans of development of capacities, job descriptions, recruitment and selection, training, efficacy assessment systems; project management; M&E; sales, strategic information systems;

Significant experience in integrated economic and social development – concretely the development of policies on entity and cantonal levels;

Other experience:

- Experience in business and public sectors;
- Experience in all administrational levels in Bosnia and Herzegovina;
- Experience in the organization and leading of workshops, task forces, focus groups etc.;
- Development of sector analyses and socioeconomic developmental strategies;
- Market research, market analysis and preparation of marketing strategies for more than 30 enterprises in the region;
- Writing of projects and project management, experience in EU projects and projects of other donors;
- Experience in the work with international organizations such as the EU, UNDP, GIZ, USAID;
- · Experience in starting businesses

Experienced Assistant Professor with a demonstrated history of working in the higher education industry. Skilled in Business Planning, Analytical Skills, Entrepreneurship, Communication, and Market Research. Strong education professional with a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) focused in Business/Managerial Economics from Faculty of Economics, University in Sarajevo.

Experience

International BURCH University
Vice Rector for Scientific Research and Interuniversity Cooperation
December 2019 - Present
Saraievo

International BURCH University Associate Professor November 2019 - Present Sarajevo

GIZ

Strategy and Development Management Expert January 2012 - Present Sarajevo

UNDP

Strategy and Development Management Expert, Team Leader January 2010 - Present

Sarajevo

Impact Consulting
Entrepreneur
January 2010 - Present
Sarajevo

International BURCH University
Vice Rector for Planning and Development
September 2017 - December 2019 (2 years 4 months)
Sarajevo

International BURCH University

Assistant Professor

February 2015 - November 2019 (4 years 10 months)

Sarajevo

www.ibu.edu.ba

European Union Delegation to Bosnia and Herzegovina Strategy and Development Management Expert/Capacity Building Expert

October 2013 - April 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Sarajevo

USAID

Evaluation Expert, Capacity Building Expert May 2014 - September 2014 (5 months) Sarajevo

Education

Faculty of Economics, University in Sarajevo Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Business/Managerial Economics · (2009 - 2014)

Henderson State University

MBA, Business Administration and Management, General · (2008 - 2009)

University of Buckingham

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science · (2004 - 2008)